Finding Aid for the Allen Family Collection of Kennedy-Johnson Inaugural Ephemera LSC.1751
UCLA Library Special Collections
Allen family collection of Kennedy-Johnson inaugural ephemera
1961-1963
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.1751
2 oversize_boxes
The collection consists mainly of ephemera and printed material, a ball gown worn by the donor's mother to the Inauguration Ball, publications such as "Life" and "Look" and newspapers which cover the Kennedy inauguration and assassination. This collection also includes ephemera from the California Governor Brown's Inauguration.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Judith A. and Gene Tuch in memory of Marian and Albert H. Allen, 2007.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9959980653606533
Biography
Marian and Albert H. Allen attended the Kennedy-Johnson Inauguration in 1961. Marian Allen (1917-2003) and Albert H. Allen (d. 2002) married in 1939. Mr. Allen was one of the longest practicing attorneys in California, practicing real estate law in Beverly Hills for nearly 70 years.
Scope and Content
The John F. Kennedy Collection of Inaugural and Assassination Ephemera consists of invitations and tickets from the John F. Kennedy Presidential Inauguration, menus, magazines, newspapers and the ball gown worn by the donor's mother, Marian Allen, to the Inauguration Ball. Publications such as "Life" and "Look" cover the Kennedy inauguration and assassination as well as newspapers and newspaper clippings from Los Angeles and Washington. This collection also includes ephemera from the California Governor Brown's Inauguration. The bulk of the collection dates from 1961-1963.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
John F. Kennedy inaugural material
Edmund G. Brown inaugural material
Ephemera.; Evening dresses (garments).; Presidents -- United States -- Inauguration -- Archives.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963--Inauguration, 1961--Archives.
- John F. Kennedy inaugural material, Series 1.
  - Ephemera, Subseries 1.
    - Campaign button for John F. Kennedy (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Inaugural Guidebook, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Invitation to Inaugural Ball, 1961 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Scope and Contents note
      Invitation to the Inaugural Ball with envelope and RSVP card. 5 items.
    - Invitation to Inaugural Gala, 1961 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Engraved invitation, hard card stock sheet, and envelope.
    - Invitation to Inaugural Gala from the Democratic National Committee at the Armory, 1961 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Invitation and envelope.
    - Invitation to reception honoring Mr. James Edward Day, Postmaster General-Designate, 1961 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Official Inaugural photo of Marian and Albert H. Allen in Ball Gown with official seal 8x10" black and white photo, 1961 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Marian Allen is wearing the I Magnin ball gown in this photo, which is part of this collection.
    - Official Inaugural Program, 1961 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      The official Inaugural Program for John F. Kennedy and Lyndon B. Johnson, January 20, 1961 with envelope.
    - Programs--Inaugural Gala, 1961 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Two Inaugural Gala programs in honor of the inauguration of John Fitzgerald Kennedy and Lyndon Baines Johnson at the Armory, Washington D.C. Includes photographs of Jacqueline Kennedy, John F. Kennedy, Lady Bird Johnson, Lydon B. Johnson, Harry S. Truman, Eleanor Roosevelt, and gala entertainers: Harry Belafonte, Milton Berle, Leonard Bernstein, Joey Bishop, Nat Cole, Tony Curtis, Bette Davis, Jimmy Durante, Ella Fitzgerald, Mahalia Jackson, Gene Kelly, Alan King, Peter Lawford, Janet Leigh, Frederic March, Ethel Merman, Sir Laurence Olivier, Sidney Poitier, Keely Smith, Louis Prima, Juliet Prowse, Anthony Quinn, Nelson Riddle, Frank Sinatra, Pat Suzuki, and Helen Traubel.
    - Reception Menu, [1961] (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Tickets to Inaugural, 1961 [January] (Box 1, Folder 11)
      1 Presidential Inauguration Ticket- silver
      3 Inaugural Platform tickets, January 20, 1961 - green
      4 Inauguration tickets - blue and grey
      3 Texas State Society Reception honoring VP elect Lyndon B. Johnson tickets
      1 Democratic National Convention ticket
      1 Democratic National Committee Inaugural Gala contribution card for free ticket.
  - Publications, Subseries 2.
    - Inaugural Spectacle: by the editors of Life, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Special edition magazine, "Inaugural Spectacle: by the editors of Life, Souvenir Edition 50¢
    - Kennedy and his family in pictures: by the editors of Look, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Magazine: "Kennedy And His Family: By the Editors of Look, with exclusive pictures from the files of Look, One Dollar."
    - Life: November 29, 1963, 1963 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Magazine: "Life: November 29, 1963 25¢ Caption reads, "President John F. Kennedy 1917-1963."
    - Life: December 6, 1963, 1963 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Magazine: "Life: December 6, 1963, 25¢ Caption reads, "Mrs. Kennedy, Caroline and John Jr. wait to join procession to capitol."
    - Post: In Memoriam: A senseless tragedy, the New President, 1963 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Magazine "Post: The Saturday Evening Post December 14, 1963 20¢: In Memoriam: A Senseless Tragedy, The New President, John F. Kennedy 1917-1963" Portrait on front cover by Norman Rockwell.
    - Newspapers and Clippings, 1961-1963; 18 clippings pasted on paper. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Portions or whole of the following newspapers:
      The Washington Post, January 20, 1961
      The Washington Post, January 21, 1961
      Citizen-News (Los Angeles), November 22,1963
      Herald Examiner (Los Angeles), November 22, 1963 (2 copies)
      Times Classified Ads (Los Angeles), November 23,1963
      The Los Angeles Times, November 23, 1963
      The New York Times, November 25, 1963.
  - Textiles, 1961; Subseries 3.
    - Inaugural Ball Gown, 1961 January 20 (Box 3)
      I Magnin ball gown worn by Mrs. Allen to the Kennedy-Johnson Inauguration.
- Edmund G. Brown inaugural material, Series 2.
  - Invitation to inaugural brunch, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Invitation from the California Democratic Congressional Delegation to a Brunch for Californians at the Mayflower Hotel
    Inaugural Activities Calendar and Information
    Democratic National Committee Memorandum Re Inauguration.
  - Program, 1963 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Inaugural Ceremony and Joint Legislative Session Program. 2 copies.
  - Program, 1963 January 6-8 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    California Governor Brown's Inaugural Sacramento Tour Program.
  - Program and tickets, 1963 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Governor's Inaugural Celebration
    Sacramento Memorial Auditorium
    Inaugural Dance, El Dorado Hotel Program. 2 copies
    One inauguration ticket and one inaugural dance ticket.